Guide to the Lauchlin Bernard Currie Papers, 1931-1994 and undated (bulk 1950-1990) RL.00277
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lauchlin Bernard Currie papers
1931-1994 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Currie, Lauchlin Bernard
RL.00277
60.35 Linear Feet
English.
31,370 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The collection was received as a gift of the estate of Lauchlin Bernard Currie in 1998 and as a gift from another donor in 1998 and 1999.
Biographical Note
Chronology
1902 Born, Nova Scotia
1922-1925 Studied at the London School of Economics
1931 Ph.D. in Economics from Harvard
1934 The Supply and Control of Money in theUnited States published.
1939 Appointed Assistant on Economic Affairs by Franklin D. Roosevelt.
1943-1944 Acting Director of the Foreign Economic Administration
1954 Loses U.S. Citizenship after being investigated by Senator Joseph McCarthy.
1949-1993 Advisor on economic issue to the government of Colombia.
1993 Died in Colombia.
Lauchlin Bernard Currie (1902-1993) was an influential economist, advisor to President Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1939-1945, and to the government of Colombia, 1949-1993. He was involved with the Lend-Lease Program with China during WWII, and became acting director of the Foreign Economic Administration in 1943-44. This work resulted in his being a target during the McCarthy era and he lost his US citizenship in 1954. He settled in Colombia after 1954 and continued to serve as an advisor to the leaders of that country until his death in 1993.
Collection Overview
The Lauchlin Bernard Currie Papers, 1930-1997, serve to document the life, career, and theories of the economist. The collection chiefly consists of correspondence, published, materials, clippings, and subject files, and is primarily arranged chronologically and thematically. The bulk of the materials focus on Currie's analysis of macroeconomic policy during the New Deal, and growth, housing, and export policies for developing countries, especially Colombia. There is also material on China and Currie's mentor at Harvard Allyn Young
Arrangement note
Note: The Printed Materials Series of the Lauchlin Bernard Currie Papers has been processed and inventoried at an item level, but the Personal Papers Series beginning with Box 9 is unprocessed and requires careful handling, as many of the materials are fragile. The main collection (Acc. 1998-0039) is in the original order it was received with the exception of two accessions folded in after 1998 (1998-0349, 1999-0172). Small groups of materials received post-processing (2000-0251, 2001-0164, 2003-0208, and 2012-0051) are also listed. Folder groups headed only by a date span generally contain articles, reports, and correspondence on a wide variety of economic and socio-political subjects chiefly relating to plans for Colombia's economic development (headed by Currie) or to theories of development in poor nations. For more information on Currie's life, see the inventory files.
Economic development -- History -- 20th century; Economics -- History; New Deal, 1933-1939; Economists -- United States -- Correspondence; Colombia-Economic policy; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities; United States -- Economic policy -- 1933-1945; Macroeconomics; Economists -- United States; China -- Economic policy; Industrialization; Developing countries -- Economic policy; Currie, Lauchlin Bernard; Young, Allyn Abbott, 1876-1929
- Printed Materials Series
  - Urbanizacion y Desarrollo, Currie, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Urbanizacion y Desarrollo, Currie, 1988 (Box 1)
  - El plan de desarrollo colombiano enmarcha, Currie, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Taming the Megalopolis: A Design for UrbanGrowth, Currie, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Bases de un programa de fomento para Colombia, Informe de una mision dirigida, Currie, y auspiciada por el Banco Internacional de Reconstruccion y Fomento (World Bank), 1951 (Box 1)
  - Journal of Economic Studies, New Series, Vol. 1, No. 1, May 1974, includes article by Currie: The 'Leading Sector' Model Growth in Developing Countries (Box 1)
  - Journal of Economic Studies, New Series Vol. 2, No. 1, May 1975, Includes article by Currie: Wants, Needs, Well-being, and Economic growth. (Box 1)
  - Journal of Economic Studies, New Series Vol. 3, No. 2, November 1976, Includes article by Currie: Comment on The Leading Sector Development Strategy-ARe-Interpretation (Box 1)
  - Controversia, Currie, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Reorganizacion de la rama ejecutiva del gobierno de Colombia, Report of a mission directed by Currie, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Report of the Economic Development Committee, Bogota, Colombia, Spanish, 1950 September-1951 August (Box 1)
  - Una politica urbana para los paises en Desarrollo, Currie, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Obstacles to Development, Currie, 1967 (Box 1)
  - History of Political Economy, Volume 12, Number 3, Fall 1980, Includes article by Currie: Causes of the Recession (1938) (Box 1)
  - Controversias sobre economia Colombiana, Chapter 8 by Currie: La economia del crecimientourbano. 1976 (Box 1)
  - Journal of Economic Studies, Vol.17, Nos. 3/4, 1990, Nicholas Kaldor's "Notes on Allyn Young's LSE Lectures, 1927-29," Includes chapter by Currie: Recollections of Allyn Young (Box 1)
  - I Congreso Nacional del Ahorro: Memoria, Includes chapter by Currie: Especializacion financiera, 1991 (Box 1)
  - El credito de vivienda: pasado, presente, futuro, Includes chapter by Currie: El Sistema UPAC Despues de Veinte Años, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Desarrollo y sociedad, 1989 March, Article by Currie: Productividad, crecimiento economico ydistribucion: relaciones conceptuales (Box 1)
  - Desarrollo y sociedad, 1991 September, Includesarticle by Currie: El dinero y el ahorro: Como las definiciones pueden afectar las politicas (Box 1)
  - Desarrollo y sociedad, 1992 March, Includes article by Currie: Una ilustracion sobre la operacion de las fuerzas del mercado (Box 1)
  - Revista de planacion y desarrollo, Vol. 18, Nos. 3-4, 1986 December, Article by Currie: La evolucion de una teoria general dereactivacion y crecimiento (Box 1)
  - Currie's PhD Thesis, 1931 (revised 1932): Bank Assets and Banking Theory (Box 2)
  - 1965 report Plan socio-economico para el Atlantico, Currie (with Fundacion para el Progreso de Colombia) (4 folders) (Box 2)
  - Report of the Economic Development Committee, Bogota, Colombia, Spanish, 1950 September-1951 August (Box 2)
  - Report of the Economic Development Committee of the World Bank, English, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Evaluacion de la asesoria economica a los paises en desarrollo: el caso colombiano, Currie, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Salitre: Una vision no realizada, Currie, 1993 September (Box 2)
  - Implications of an Endogenous Theory of Growth Based on Allyn Young's Macroeconomic Concept of Increasing Returns, Currie, 1993 (Box 2)
  - The Economic Journal, 1971 (Box 2)
  - The Economic Journal, 1973 (Box 2)
  - Reforma urbana y des arrollosocial, Fabio Giraldo Isaza, editor. Includes chapter by Currie: Algunos aspectos de la economiaurbana, 1989 February (Box 2)
  - Administracion publica en Colombia, Currie, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Informe annual del consejo nacional deplanificacion, año 1952, Currie, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Desarrollo autosostenido de Colombia, 1986, Chapter by Currie: Crecimiento conestabilidad (Box 2)
  - Modelos economicos de desarrollo Colombiano, Chapter by Currie: Aspectos macroeconomicos de la politícaurbana, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Moneda en Colombia: comportamiento y control, Currie, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Moneda en Colombia: comportamiento y control, Currie, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Controversia sobre el plan de vivienda sinquota inicial, Fabio Giraldo Isaza, ed. Articles by Currie: Nuevas reflexiones sobre oferta y demand de vivienda and La vivienda como un instrumento depolítica macroeconomica, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Journal of Economic Studies, New Series Vol. 6, No. 1, 1979 May, Includes article by Currie: Is there an Urban Bias? Critique of Michael Lipton's 'Why Poor People Stay Poor' (Box 2)
  - Journal of Economic Studies, Vol. 10, No. 3, 1983, Article by Currie: The 'Multiplier' in Economic Literature (Box 2)
  - UPAC: Una teoria convertida en exitosa realidad, Lauchlin Currie and Luis Eduardo Rosas, Spanish, 1986 (Box 2)
  - UPAC: A Theory Converted into a Successful Reality, Currie and Luis Eduardo Rosas, English, 1986 (Box 2)
  - UPAC: Una teoria convertida en exitosa realidad, Currie and Luis Eduardo Rosas, Spanish, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Reactivacíon, crecimiento, y estabilidad, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Recursos para el futuro: Colombia1950-2000, Currie is listed as a colaborador, 1981 (Box 2)
  - La politica urbana en un marco macroeconomico: una seleccion de los escritos de los ultimos diez anos, Currie, 1975-1982 (Box 2)
  - Politicas de crecimiento y desarrollo, Currie, 1982 (Box 2)
  - Plan socio-economico para el Atlantico, Currie, 1965 (Box 2)
  - The Basis of a Development Program for Colombia, Report of a Mission headed by Lauchlin Currie, sponsored by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Economia Colombiana: revista de la contraloria general de la Republica, 1973 September-October.Includes: El sistema colombiano de ahorro y vivienda, Currie, pp. 44-59 (Box 3)
  - Identidad de los intereses de una clase deun pais, Lauchlin Currie. Texto de la exposicion pronunciada en el Salon de Conferencias de la Camara de Comercio de Bucaramanga, 1964 30 October (Box 3)
  - Habitat International: A Journal for the Study of Human Settlements Established at the United Nations Habitat Conference. Vol. 4, No. 3, 1979Includes: For Whom Should New Housing be Built? Currie, 291-298 (Box 3)
  - Guidelines for a New Strategy, The National Planning Department, Bogota, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Reprint of Treatment of Credit in Contemporary Monetary Theory, Currie, Journal of Political Economy, Vol.XLI, No. 1, February 1933 (Box 3)
  - Reprint of The Failure of Monetary Policy to Prevent the Depression of 1929-1932, Currie, Journal of Political Economy, Vol.XLII, No. 2, 1934 April (Box 3)
  - Problemas economicos de la mayoria de los paises latinoamericanos, Currie, Una Publicacion de la Camara de Comercio de Barranquilla. 1964 September (Box 3)
  - La enseñanza de la economia en Colombia: ¿Como? ¿Para quien? ¿Sobre que? ¿Por que? Currie, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Ahorro y vivienda, 1973 October-December. El ahorro, la construccion y elingreso, Currie, pp. 15-20 (Box 3)
  - Politica agraria y desarrollo economico: La industria ganadera y la nacion, Currie, Una Publicacion del Banco deColombia y Almacenes Generales de Deposito Mercantil, S.A. 1962 June (Box 3)
  - Consideraciones sobre la politica agraria colombiana, Currie, 1962 (Box 3)
  - The Objectives of a National Economic Program, Currie, Bogota, 1962 March, Fundacion Parael Progreso de Colombia (Box 3)
  - Economia Colombiana: revista de la contraloria general de la Republica, 1972 February, Diferencias entre el nuevo plan y anteriores planes de desarrollo, Currie, pp. 24-29 (Box 3)
  - La conexion del ferrocarril del Atlantico con Barranquilla y las posibilidades de desacacion y aprovechamiento economicode 135,000 hectares adyacentes a la Cienaga Grande de Santa Marta, Separata dela memoria del Ministro de Obras Publicas Virgilio Barco Vargas, a la Legislatura Ordinaria de 1960 del Congreso de la Republica de Colombia. Chapter 2: Consideraciones economicas sobre el ferrocarril del Atlantico, Currie y Henry Eder (Box 3)
  - Guion: revista semanal de hecho yopiniones, 1979 December17-23, El hecho economico de la decada: Lacreacion de un instrumento de desarrollo, Currie, pp.251-253 (Box 3)
  - Arco: revista de temas deactualidad, 1973 February, Una politica urbana para Colombia, Currie (Box 3)
  - Desarrollo y Sociedad, 1983 August. La unidad de poder adquisitivo constanto: Una breve historia acerca de su nascimiento, Currie, pp.1-12 (Box 3)
  - Una nota sobre planes nacionales ymodelos, Currie. In Desarrollo y Sociedad, no. 14, 1984 May (Box 3)
  - Arco: revista de temas deactualidad, 1973 August, "Bogota en 1990," Currie, pp.28-34 (Box 3)
  - Operacion Colombia: Un programa nacionalde desarrollo economico y social, Currie, Jun-1961 August (Box 3)
  - Cabildo: Organo de la asociacion colombiana de municipalidades, 1966 December, Planeamiento Regional y Urbano, Currie, pp. 7-14 (Box 3)
  - Informe del visitador Lauchlin Currie sobre la escuela de economia para graduados, Universidad de los Andes, 1964, April (Box 3)
  - Estudio agro-economico preliminar del valle aluvial del Rio Sinu. Fundacion para el Progreso de Colombia, Asesor General, Currie, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Revista de planeacion y desarrollo, vol. 5, no. 2, April-June, 1973. Currie: La politica monetaria y el nivel deprecios, pp. 20-45 (Box 3)
  - Revista de planeacion y desarrollo, vol. 5, no. 3, July-1973 December (Box 3)
  - International Financing of EconomicDevelopment, World Scientific Banking Meeting. Dubrovnik, 31 October-1977, 5November. Factors Conditioning the InternationalFinancing of Scientific and Technical Research for DevelopingCountries, Currie (Box 3)
  - Revista de planeacion ydesarrollo, vol. III, no. 3, 1971 October La limitacion de las divisas aldesarrollo: una solucion parcial al problema, Currie, pp.3-24 (Box 3)
  - The Interrelations of Urban and NationalEconomic Planning, Currie, Urban Studies (1975), 12,pp.37-46 (Box 3)
  - On Lauchlin Currie's Contribution toMonetary Theory, Karl Brunner, 1934 (Box 3)
  - Ensayos sobre planeacion: introduccion auna teoria de desarrollo conocida como Operacion Colombia, Currie, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Keynesian Revolution - Discussion, comment by Currie in American Economic Review, 1972 May (Box 3)
  - The Role of Economic Advisors inDeveloping Countries, Currie, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Moliarrox: Revista bimensual al serviciode los molineros y cultivadores de arroz, 1962 March. Vol. 2, no. 5.Includes article by Currie: La Operacion Colombia. (Box 3)
  - Revista de planeacion ydesarrollo, vol. 8, no. 3, September-1976 December (Box 3)
  - Article by Currie: Planeacion metropolitana: Moscu yBogota, pp. 105-112 (Box 3)
  - Operacion Colombia: Un programa nacionalde desarrollo economico y social, Currie. June-1961 August (Box 3)
  - Enseñanza universitaria en los estudiossociales, Currie, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Algunas barricades en la via deldesarrollo, Currie, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Journal of Economic Studies, vol.8, No. 1, 1981, Currie: Allyn Young and the Development of GrowthTheory, pp. 52-60. (Box 3)
  - Program of Economic Development of theMagdalena Valley and North of Colombia. Report of a Mission directed byCurrie, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Programa de desarrollo economico del Valledel Magdalena y norte de Colombia, Informe de una mission dirigida porCurrie, Bogota, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Folders containing typescript: "Population, Resources, and the Environmentin Columbia's [sic] Future, Currie with the assistance of James Hanson, vol. I and vol. II, ca. 1978 (Box 4)
  - Accelerating Development: The Necessityand the Means, Currie, McGraw-Hill Series in International Development, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Desarrollo economico acelarado: Lanecesidad y los medios, Currie, Fondo de Cultura Economica, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Informe sobre un estudio economico delDepartamento Norte de Santander, Contratado or el Ministerio de Fomento,dirigido por Currie, Bogota, 1962 August (Box 4)
  - Informe sobre un estudio economico delDepartamento del Meta, contratado pro el Departamento Administrativo dePlaneacion y Servicios Tecnicos, dirigido por Currie, Bogota, 1961 August (Box 4)
  - El algodon en Colombia: problemas yoportunidades, estudio dirgido por Currie, Bogota, 1963 December (Box 4)
  - Carta de ahorro y vivienda, Numero3 y 4, April-May de 1992 (Box 4)
  - Carta de ahorro y vivienda, Numero5, Junio de 1992 (Box 4)
  - Estudio agro-economico prelimar: playonesde los municipios de plato y pinto, Currie, Asesor General, Bogota, 1962 April (Box 4)
  - La "Operacion Colombia" y suscriticas, Currie, Bogota, 1962 March (Box 4)
  - Texto del reportaje concedido por elProfesor Lauchlin Currie al Programa "Cinco reporteros y el personaje de lasemana," Bogota, 1962 April (Box 4)
  - Javeriana, el pensamiento cristiano endialogo con el mundo, Año 56, No. 543, Abril 1988. ¿Quien es el responsable de la politicaeconomica? Currie (Box 4)
  - La ganaderia de carne en Colombia,sociedad de agricultores y ganaderos de valle del Cauca S.A.G. 1981 May, Capitulo I: La Industria Ganadera, Currie (Box 4)
  - Revista camara de comercio deBogota, Año 3, Numero 9, Bogota, 1972 December, El ahorro y el plan de desarrollo, Currie (Box 4)
  - Ganaderia, Revista de la federacionantioqueña de ganaderos, 1962, Includes twoarticles by Currie (Box 4)
  - Economia Colombiana, Revista de lacontraloria general de la Republica, 1973 Julio - Agosto, Contabilidad fiscal y planeacion, Currie (Box 4)
  - Curso de planificacion del desarrolloagricola, 1967: Seleccion deConferencias y ejercicios. Consequencias de la tecnificacion agricolaen los paises subdesarrollos, Currie (Box 4)
  - La demanda de dinero y la velocidadingreso de la moneda en Colombia 1960 - 1980, Currie, Desarrollo y Sociedad, No. 6,Julio de 1981 (Box 4)
  - Population Bulletin, Vol. XXIII,No. 2, 1967 April, The Tangled Crisis, Currie (Box 4)
  - Proyecciones de la demanda deconstrucciones y de materiales para construccion en Colombia para el periodo1962-1970, Currie y Hugo Belalcazar L., Bogota, Marzo de 1963 (Box 4)
  - Plan de fomento para el Atlantico, 1954 March (Box 4)
  - Guion, cover story: El Professor Currie: 30 años enColombia. 1979 September10-16 (Box 4)
  - Journal of Economic Issues, Vol.III, No. 2, 1969 June, Myrdal on South Asia, Currie (Box 4)
  - The Xavieran, 1921 February, St. FrancisXavier's College, Antigonish, Nova Scotia. From Coast to Coast in a Car, Currie (Box 4)
  - The Xavieran, 1922 February (Box 4)
  - Bases de un programa de fomento paraColombia: informe de una mission dirigida por Lauchlin Currie y auspiciada porel banco internacional de reconstruccion y fomento en colaboracion con elgobierno de Colombia, Agosto de 1950 (Box 4)
  - Estudio de previabilidad SansFacon-Paloquemao-Usatama, preparado por The American City Corporation, 1976 April, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Estudio sobre Teoria Macroeconomica yPoliticas de Crecimiento. 1990 July 19 (Box 4)
  - Nicholas Kaldor's "Notes on Allyn Young's London School of EconomicsLectures, 1927-29." 1989 December21 (Box 4)
  - 21 issues of Carta de Ahorro y Vivienda. 1987 September to 1989 July (Box 4)
  - Comision del Gasto Publico: Informefinal, 1986: the Commissionincludes Currie (Box 5)
  - Investigation of Concentration of EconomicPower, Hearings before the Temporary National Economic Committee Congress ofthe United States, 1939 May: includestestimony from Currie, Assistant Director, Division of Research and Statistics,Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, Washington,D.C. (Box 5)
  - Address by Currie before the American Academy of Political and Social Sciences,Bellevue Stratford Hotel, Philadelphia, PA., 1950 April 15, Some Prerequisites for Success of thePoint Four Program (Box 5)
  - Appendix: Appendices A and B to MiltonFriedman's Money Series 1867-1960 and Reserves 1867-1960, CapitalFlows (Box 5)
  - La industria cafeteria en la agriculturacolombiana, 1962, Estudio realizadopor la Fundacion para el Progresso de Colombia (Box 5)
  - Report from the RockefellerFoundation, 1972 September (In Englishand Spanish) (Box 5)
  - Plan para Bogota, 1953, Consejo Nacional dePlanificacion (Box 5)
  - Theoretical Background and ProbableOrientation of the Colombian Urban Study for ILPES, Currie, 1975 October 22 (Box 5)
  - Estudio de previabilidad SansFacon-Paloquemao-Usatama, preparado por The American City Corporation, 1976 April (Box 5)
  - Un desiño para el crecimientourbano, Currie, 1976 (Box 5)
  - Comments on a "Review of ConceptualFormulations," Statements by the Representatives of Colombia, 1975 September22-26 (Box 5)
  - La interrelacion de la planeacion urbana yregional con la planeacion nacional, economica y social, Currie,Instituto de Estudios Colombianos, 1976 January (Box 5)
  - La interrelacion de la planeacion urbana yregional con la planeacion nacional, economica y social, Currie,Instituto de Estudios Colombianos, 1977 June (Box 5)
  - La economia del crecimientourbano, Currie, Segundo Seminario de Economia Colombiana, 1975 April (Box 5)
  - Colombian Urban Policy in the Plan ofDevelopment, 1974 January (Box 5)
  - Criteria for Multinational FinancialAssistance in Urban Development, Currie, 1975 (Box 5)
  - Indexation: Selective orComprehensive? Currie, Seminar on Indexation, Sao Paulo, Brazil, 1975 February26-28 (Box 5)
  - Estudio de previabilidad SansFacon-Paloquemao-Usatama, preparado por The American City Coporation, 1976 April (Box 5)
  - La interrelacion de la planeacion urbana yregional con la planeacion nacional, economica y social, escrito porCurrie, Instituto Latinoamericano de Planificacion Economica y Social(ILPES), 14-15, 1976 June (Box 5)
  - The Indexation ofSavings/Mortgages, Currie, 1976 September10 (Box 5)
  - Politica monetaria deestabilizacion, 1977 May 25 (Box 5)
  - 21 Issues of Carta de Ahorro y Vivienda, 1987 September-1989July (Box 5)
  - Urbanizacion: algunos aspectosbasicos, Currie. United Nations Conference on Human Settlements, 31May-11 June, 1976 (Box 5)
  - La construccion de vivienda y elcrecimiento economico, Currie, 1989 October (Box 5)
  - La evolucion de una teoria general dereactivacion y crecimiento, Currie, 1987 February2 (Box 5)
  - The Demand for Money and its Velocity:Some Implications, Currie, 1986 May 6 (Box 5)
  - Summary of Report on Some Aspects ofPublic Administration in Colombia, Currie, 1986 December and 1987 January (Box 5)
  - Housing as an Instrument of MacroeconomicPolicy, 1987 November (Box 5)
  - Moneda en Colombia, Currie, 1987 August (Box 5)
  - Contrato de consultoria para larealizacion del estudio sobre las bases de la politica macroeconomica de laadministracion publica, Currie, 1987 December (Box 5)
  - Algunas reflexiones sobre la deudaexterna, Currie, 1988 November (Box 5)
  - Alternativas de politicaeconomica, Currie, Bogota, May 23, 1990 For the Centro deEstudios sobre Desarrollo Economico (CEDE) (Box 5)
  - La asesoria economica en Colombia, Currie, [1988] (Box 5)
  - Economic Advising in Colombia, Currie, 1988 December23 (Box 5)
  - The American Economic Review, bookreview by Currie (Box 5)
  - Addresses delivered during the convocation excercises atSimon Fraser University, 1981 June 6, Currie on Economic Growth, Development and Survival (Box 5)
  - El Salitre: plan de integracionurbana. Instituto de Desarrollo Urbano, [1975] (Box 5)
  - Politicas de incentivos al sectorexterno, Currie, Bogota, 1984 October (Box 6)
  - Recopilacion de licencias de construcciónen Bogota, Alvaro Montenegro Garcia (Box 6)
  - Memoranda for the Transition Period of1986, Currie (Box 6)
  - Aspectos macroeconomicos de la politicafiscal, Currie, 1986 June (Box 6)
  - Reservas internacionales y reactivacioneconomica, Currie and Alvaro Montenegro Garcia, 1985 (Box 6)
  - The Use of the Multiplier Concepts inEconomic Literature, Currie, 1983 May 11 (Box 6)
  - Asociacion foro economico nacional:politica de vivienda en Colombia, Bogota, 1981 November 2 (Box 6)
  - Housing as an Instrument of Macro-economicPolicy, Currie, Habitat International, Vol. 7, No.5/6, pp. 165-171, 1983 (Box 6)
  - Politica Macroeconomica, Primer Semestre, 1983, Currie, Centro deEstudios sobre Desarrollo Economico (CEDE), Facultad deEconomía, Universidad de Los Andes, Bogota, Colombia (Box 6)
  - "Some Suggestions for the Improvement of theInstitutional Framework for Macroeconomic Policy," 1987 January 2 (Box 6)
  - Desarrollo urbano y areasmetropolitanas, Currie y Alvaro Montenegro, 1985 (Box 6)